hello okay guys I'm gonna try this again
but here's what I'm gonna try to do I
think I'm gonna go do question and
answers over at Eric our Weinstein on
Instagram and I'm just going to do a
sort of a short video here so that if
you guys want to join it would be an
absolute pleasure to walk with you and
take questions and have conversations
which I like doing often better than
monologues but I just wanted to say a
couple of things which are on my mind
which have to do in part with a very odd
tweet that I saw today and the very odd
tweet was from Matt Iglesias over at Vox
media and it had to do with the fact
that he was taking responsibility oddly
for having screwed up the idea that woke
nizam or serious problem when taken very
into very extreme lengths and that that
problem was not confined as he had
thought to college campuses so the you
know the old idea was hey it's a couple
of kids with green hair and you guys are
getting incredibly bent out of shape
about it right however what was really
going on is is that college campuses and
academics have a delayed effect in fact
a lot of these ideas like
intersectionality came out of UCLA
unexamined privilege came out of
Wellesley many of these things started
in like either the late 70s 80s or early
90s so a lot of what we talk about today
is actually from academics and academic
it takes a while for the stuff to to
percolate now I don't actually even
believe that most of what's going on
right now is peculiar to policing to the
United States to race relations those
all play into it but I think that it's
in fact like if you had headed somebody
dying in immigration custody we could
have everyone in the streets over
immigration
rather than everyone in the streets over
police
tality or racism so mad Iglesias was
sort of opining that things had gotten
really out of control and he was going
to have to take responsibility that he'd
actually gotten the stuff wrong well
somebody's reading boiling point in some
sense what I was saying is it's a
supersaturated environment and it
doesn't take much to create a phase
transition you just need a nucleating
event and so we got a nucleating event
and now we're endlessly discussing the
nucleating event rather than the
supersaturated environment which has to
do with the fact that I don't think the
people in our sense-making apparatus and
the media and political parties and
academics are either brave they're not
both brave and smart they're if they're
one they're not the other and very often
they're neither so what does this have
to do with shame shame was in the title
well I want to launch a thought with you
guys and I'll develop maybe on the
podcast which is are we in the middle of
a worldwide shame fetish is there
something about our phones that have
actually activated our bizarre sort of
fetishistic thought processes so that we
are taking part in some incredibly weird
game and I was thinking about narcissus
and Ecco
I guess avid was the one who sort of
augmented the narcissus myth to include
Ecco who falls in love with the beloved
but the beloved notice is only the self
and I was thinking about looking at some
videos of people in one case kissing the
shoes of a very bizarre group of black
men who were demanding that white people
kissed their shoes and another one where
somebody has told that somebody's from
black lives matter I don't think they
were was probably in a posture but you
know would you kneel please and I was
thinking about all the bizarre things
that have to do with knees at the moment
like okay Game of Thrones as my friend
Douglas Murray points out put the
concept of bend the knee into the world
there's a concept of Colin Kaepernick
taking the knee there's obviously a
sexual connotation to knees you you
kneel before the Queen when you're being
knighted you may kneel together in
common prayer you kneel when you're
alone and asking something from the
Creator and somehow I think this is
incredibly weird and I think it's also
incredibly disturbing and so what I keep
wanting to ask is are we looking for
equality I have always thought that
racial equality sexual equality various
kinds of equality were really important
either we are looking for it or we
aren't if we are looking for it I want
me to say the following
I may get on my knees with you if we are
both moved in a moment but if you ask
ever for me to get on my knees before
you you've just killed all hope of
equality and I was thinking about the
idea of what I as a Jewish person ever
want a German person to kneel before me
and kiss my shoes and the thought is
like it doesn't even come up in my mind
it makes me sick to my stomach this
concept of a lie ship and whiteness and
anti blackness is a mind trap it's a
really dangerous idea and it's going to
destroy the project that so many of us
have been working on for forever which
is how do we get a decent country in
which the color of one's skin is no bar
and that we can be positive about who we
are and I think that what's going on is
is that we are in a worldwide shame
fetish you know we're talking about
shaming and fat shaming and every kind
of possible shame imaginable is trading
at a premium and dignity is trading at a
deep discount so I want to leave you
guys with thought and then I want you to
follow me over to Instagram
maybe we can talk about it which would
be great where I'm Eric our Weinstein at
Instagram but are we in the middle of
something where some of us feel so
guilty that we're really kind of weirdly
getting off on humbling ourselves before
other people who feel so oppressed that
they want to oppress others and I don't
think this is the modal situation I
don't think the average person in the
street is looking for this but I think
there's a ton of this and we saw this at
Evergreen State where my brother was go
back and look at the videos and tell me
that there isn't some very weird way in
which the president of Evergreen State
College wasn't the fetishistic
accomplice of the students who were
rioting and what do we do to bring up
all of our dignity and without this kind
of obscenity of parasitizing the
responsibility that we all feel I feel
tremendous responsibility for people who
are discriminated against I think it's
part of my best nature and it's very
important that nobody parasitize or
weaponize my best instincts towards
responsibility so I just I will leave
you with one thought try to be
responsible and be very thoughtful and
caring when somebody tells you that you
haven't examined all of the ways in
which you may benefit from a system that
somebody else suffers from I think
that's entirely reasonable the instant
it turns into I've brought food for
Chinese people only or I've brought
chairs only for black people or you know
we have we have special contributions
for women who owned stores you know like
nobody else when it gets to that point
instill in yourself some kind of
revulsion because that's going to undo
the project that we've all been a part
of and quite frankly the people who are
looking for this either because they're
dying to get down on their knees or
because they demand that somebody else
get down on their knees
or the idea is that some people have it
coming because they look like other
people who are horrible these people are
going to undo a national project and
this is a long project for which many
people have suffered many people have
worked and many people have died and
quite frankly it's not up to them to
undo it because it belongs to all of us
and so my feeling about this is a modest
amount of responsibility is worth a
great deal more than an oppressive mount
amount and a self-extinguishing amount
of of performative guilt meant to convey
that you're willing to destroy your own
dignity at the drop of a hat because you
do understand that other people have had
things in life worse than you so over to
Instagram coming up at 10 minutes thanks
very much I'm just getting my 10,000
steps and for those of you who will
complain that I'm not using a selfie
stick at least I'm in landscape rather
than portrait I do listen to you guys
but I'm also not going to do everything
perfectly so thank you guys very much
Eric our Weinstein over at Instagram and
I'll try to take some questions and talk
to you guys and stay safe look out for
your fellow man and don't give up on
equality and you can't if you can't
pursue equality and groveling at the
same time from either side of the fence
be well